Dominique Northecide

THANKYOUDOM.COM | GITHUB.COM/MONSIEURVERDE

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Dominique Northecide is a full-stack web developer and UX/UI computer software designer. Contributing his technical passion and creative skills towards a career in software development and multimedia initiatives, Northecide manipulates his array of skills as a means to leverage his two years of university education in Computer Science, six months of coding bootcamp training, and BFA in Graphic Design.

SKILLS

React, Node.js, NPM GitHub Python Linux

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, threeJS Firebase (Authentication) C# Bash Command Line

Hugo (Static site generator), Jekyll Firestore / NoSQL Java

EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY

Web Developer, Belle IT, January 2021 - Present

SmartViewMD is a progressive web application (PWA) that consolidates patient vitals from 3rd party medical devices utilizing a Web Bluetooth API. The site was created using technologies such as React, JavaScript, Firebase, and Swift (native iOS App).

- Web Development: Developed website for company and product information SmartViewMD.com
- Graphic Design: Designed and created promotional materials for Belle IT Products.
- The website was created utilizing several React components, Node.js for server-side scripting and an EmailJS component for client-side email contact integration.
- Integrated React components such as react-toastify, react-bootstrap react-router-dom, and more for adding features.
- Contact form was created using third-party service, EmailJS, to send the users contact information upon entry by importing modules using npm.
- Improved the user-experience of the web app using bootstrap.
- Automated build and deployment using korn shell scripts.
- Used Github for repository and revision control.
- Created an iOS native application using Web BLE iOS app as a library.
- Maintained iOS testing environment using Test Flight
- Used Visual Studio code (vsCode) IDE and Xcode for Swift
- Product Management: Identified new product opportunities and conducted product testing with clinic patients & physicians to ensure product efficiency.

Lead Web Developer, FAUniversity Galleries,

January 2020 - November 2020

Launched a website that hosted the works of participants in a juried student art exhibition. The website was created using Hugo and exhibited a virtual experience created utilizing a combination of the ArtSteps VR platform and 3D objects exported from Blender. The virtual-reality experience of the website referenced the floor plan of the Ritter Art Gallery located on Florida Atlantic University's Boca Campus.

- Web Development: Designed and created promotional materials for the University Galleries.
- **Graphic Design:** Implemented exhibition design and production.
- Embedded ArtSteps VR experience in the site, as an iFrame, to be available for in-site and full screen viewing purposes.
- Purchased domain using NameCheap
- Managed DNS records for gitHub.io integration and automated deployment.
- Developed the website utilizing Hugo, a static site generator.
- Deployed the compiled public folder to gh-pages. <u>FAUniversityGalleries.com</u>

Lead Web Developer, PerspectiveBFA.com

2020

Set up a virtual exhibition which showcased selected works of graphic designers, as well as, redirected viewers to each designer's respective portfolios. The website was an educational web project that was created for my graduating BFA class and included a web portal that allowed the designers to input/manipulate their information which was simultaneously writing to the variables of the main website. This project was created using technologies React and Firebase.

- Used Firebase tools for user authentication for each designer
- Integrated Firestore for cloud-hosting asset management.
- Utilized CloudFlare CDN for httpS redirect of subdomain used for authentication.
- Added google analytics tag in the index.js file to monitor user engagement and track unique site visitors.
- Compiled a post-exhibition report with analytics for every designer's page, as well as the rest of the site, formatted in a pdf exported from Google sheets.
- Created a 3D experience utilizing React rendering for threeJS and several other React components
- Compiled a build folder that was deployed using Github hosting.

Collaborated & implemented designs for web and physical collateral, using technologies such as InDesign, WordPress,GoDaddy, using best practices for mobile and web-based design.

- Created & implemented revenue winning sales creative campaigns / strategies to acquire new business and grow organizational earnings.
- Supervised organization of production info for international companies e.g Famatel, Boxmark Austria using Microsoft Excel.

EDUCATION

BFA Graphic Design

LaunchCode Coding Bootcamp

BS Computer Science

Aug 2016 - Dec 2020 Florida Atlantic University Jul 2019 - Jan 2020 LaunchCode Aug 2014 - Jun 2016 Tuskegee University

Hobbies: Tennis, Coding, Drawing, Music production, 9 years of formal classical music education (piano)